Max Manders, BSc (Hons)

I am a driven and passionate web developer with experience developing for a range of architectures and environments, focussing on LAMP-stack development. I like to learn new skills and to be constantly challenged in all that I do. A proponent of web standards, open source and open data, I view the Internet as both a resource that should be available to all and a platform to enable developers to continually reinvent what the internet is, what we can do with it and what we can make it do for us.

Skills / Applications / Languages

- PHP 5
 - Frameworks: Zend Framework 1.x, Symfony 1.x, Code Igniter, LightVC
- X(HTML) / HTML5
- JavaScript
 - Frameworks: jQuery, YUI
- CSS
- OOP Design / Development
- · Subversion, Git
- Vim
- Awk, Sed
- Linux (Debian / Ubuntu)

- Unix (AIX)
- Linux System Administration
 - Apache, Lighttpd, MySQL, PostreSQL, Squid, Vagrant, Puppet
- Bash Shell Scripting
- Perl
- Python
- SQL
 - MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Informix
- Wordpress
- Zen Cart

Employment History

12/2011 - PRESENT

Roles / Responsibilities

Systems Developer / Business Analyst, Maglabs Ltd.

- Bespoke application development based on a CentOS / PHP 5 LAMP stack.
- Contribution to custom AV processing framework.
- Liaising with clients to elicit software requirements.
- Software design and specification.

08/2010 - PRESENT

Roles / Responsibilities

Systems Developer, Maglabs Ltd.

- Bespoke application development based on a CentOS / PHP 5 LAMP stack.
- Contribution to custom AV processing framework.

07/2009 - 08/2010

Roles / Responsibilities

Senior Systems Developer, Diet Chef Ltd.

- Fulfil all IT requirements of the company.
- Custom development of Zen Cart:
 - Repeat subscriptions functionality.
 - Stock control system.
 - Call-centre interface.
 - I18n and L10n to allow operations in Germany, Austria, Benelux
 - Integration with QVC data feed
 - Custom reporting for marketing analysis
- Bespoke Python GTK application to manage courier label printing.
- Implementation of Wordpress themes and plugins.
- System Administration
 - Linux, Apache, MySQL, Asterisk PABX

11/2007 - 07/2009

Roles / Responsibilities

Systems Developer, Valley Technology Ltd.

- Bespoke application development using PHP 4 / 5, MySQL/PostgreSQL
- Development of The Podfather using Symfony 1.x
- Application development, support and system

- administration for Farmfoods Ltd.
- Bash and Perl Scripting
- Terminal client development using C++/nCurses and C-ISAM against an Informix database.
- Systems Administration
 - Apache, MySQL, PostgreSQL, OpenLDAP, Exim/Postfix MTAs

02/2006 - 11/2007

Roles / Responsibilities

Web Developer, Crown Office and Procurator Fiscal Service

- · Administration of departmental Intranet.
- User support.
- Development for Oracle 9i Application Server
- Development with Oracle PL/SQL
- · Bespoke LAMP development
- · Administration of Unix AIX server
- KSH and Perl scripting
- Contributed to Java SE project to replace legacy system used to retrieve and process reports sent to COPFS from various criminal justice partners.

Education History

2001 - 2005

Heriot Watt University, Edinburgh

BSC (Hons) Computer Science

1995 - 2001

Breadalbane Academy, Aberfeldy, Perthshire

- 5 SQ Highers including Computer Science (A), Mathematics (B) and Physics (A)
- SQA Advanced Higher Pure Mathematics (B)

Selected Portfolio / Achievements

http://maxmanders.co.uk

http://ukgeocode.maxmanders.co.uk

http://datatables.org

http://whiskyweb.co.uk

- Personal blog
- Geocode UK postcodes to lat/lon coordinates.
- XML API
- Built using YQL (Yahoo Query Language)
- Schema definition and associated data endpoint to geocode UK postcodes to lat/lon coordinates.
- Schema definition and associated data endpoint providing searchable UK food nutritional data.
- Co-organiser of the inaugural Whisky Web web developer conference.